[{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Femi Osofisan's <em>Women of Owu<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>The three allied forces that attacked Owu were<\/p>","options":["Ijebu, Ogun, Ife","Ijebu, Ife, Oyo","Ode, Oyo, Ife","Ogun, Oyo, Ife"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Femi Osofisan's <em>Women of Owu<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>Who made the statement, <em>\"Do you still trust in them (gods) after this?\"<\/em><\/p>","options":["Anlugbua","Adumaadun","Gesinde","Erelu"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Femi Osofisan's <em>Women of Owu<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>The main character in Women of Owu was<\/p>","options":["Gesinde","Erelu","Adumaadun","Oba Akinjobi"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Femi Osofisan's <em>Women of Owu<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>The character that reaped the fruit of his folly in the end is<\/p>","options":["Maye Okunade","Erelu","Oba Akinjobi","Anlugbua"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Femi Osofisan's <em>Women of Owu<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>The major theme of the play is<\/p>","options":["manipulation of human beings by the gods","the destructive nature of wars","women","casualties of war"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Chimamanda Adichie's <em>Purple Hibiscus<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The subject matter of the novel is<\/p>","options":["domestic violence","religious zeal","child abuse","marital infidelity"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Chimamanda Adichie's <em>Purple Hibiscus<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>\"God knows best. God works in mysterious ways.\"<\/em><\/p>\n<p>Who made the statement and to whom?<\/p>","options":["Father Amadi\/Kambili","Aunty Ifeoma\/Kambili","Kambili\/Jaja","Obiora\/Mama"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Chimamanda Adichie's <em>Purple Hibiscus<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Which part of the South-Eastern Nigeria did Kambili and Jaja visit?<\/p>","options":["Aba","Owerri","Nsukka","Onitsha"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Chimamanda Adichie's <em>Purple Hibiscus<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The novel started with<\/p>","options":["an oxymoron","a rhetorical question","a suspense","a confusion"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on William Shakespeare's <em>Tempest<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>In the play, a character that wasn't seen is<\/p>","options":["Sycorax","Prospero","Ariel","Caliban"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on William Shakespeare's <em>Tempest<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Ariel's three evil men are<\/p>","options":["Caliban, Trinculo and Staphano","Alonso, Sebastian and Antonio","Trinculo, Sebastian and Gonzalo","Prospero, Ferdinand and Caliban"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The major theme in Asari Konadu's <em>Woman in her Prime<\/em> is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the child quest of an African woman","exploitation of the African woman","sex discrimination in Ghana","women liberation in Nigeria"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A play that stimulates the audience to excessive laughter is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["comedy","farce","climax","tragicomedy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The title of Umeh's <em>Ambassador of Poverty<\/em> is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a repitition","a simile","an alliteration","an irony"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Owonibi's <em>Homeless, not Hopeless<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>the persona explains that street beggers<\/p>","options":["always worry about heaven","attend conferences in town","are concerned with their daily needs","rarely sleep and dream"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A reference to a work of art, person or place whether directly or indirectly is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["allusion","contrast","assonance","allegory"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Literature, a Dramatis Personae refers to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the name of the author","the list of characters in a play","the name of the central character in a play","the voice of the characters in a play"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a writer refers to past events to throw more light on current ones, he is employing<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a retrospection","flashback","historical drama","dramatic shift"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a type of poem?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sonnet","Elegy","Pantomime","Ode"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major narrative technique a novel shares with drama is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["scenes","dialogue","soliloquy","sarcasm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The rivers mentioned in the novel <em>'Negro Speak of Rivers'<\/em> can be found in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["America, Europe, Asia","Asia, America, Africa","Europe, Africa, Oceania","America, Europe, Oceania"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the novel 'Purple Hisbiscus' the life of Kambili and her brother in their father's house can be said to be<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fulfilling and loving","oppressive and fearful","passive and uneventful","quiet and peaceful"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Imagery used in Adeoti Shola's <em>\"Hard lines\"<\/em> is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["disappointment and despair","contempt and disgust","sacrificial and helpful","unpleasant and difficult"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Novel <em>'The Old Man and the Sea'<\/em> can be described as...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a satire","an epic","an allegory","a love story"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>He stands there looking like he knows the secret of how our sun glows. A myth has been well propagated that power - nuclear's the source (it fit the theory once of course), but now new theories are debated.<\/strong><\/em>&nbsp;<\/p>\n<p>The rhyme scheme of the stanza above is<\/p>","options":["ababcc","ababab","aabccb","aabbcc"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A blank verse<\/p>","options":["is a nonsensical verse","consists of unrhymed five stress lines","is a verse used by the nobility","consists of rhyme in the second and fourth line"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The technique used in bringing the plot of a play to an abrupt end is called<\/p>","options":["denouement","climax","endnote","dues ex machina"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>\"Stream of consciousness\" is the name for&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["a narrative mode that produces a character's random thoughts and association","an Italian rhyme scheme brought into vogue in the sixteenth century","a stage device in which an actor addresses the audience directly","a cultural phenomenon of the eighteenth century"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>B<\/strong><strong>ased in William Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>\"Wisely and slow. They stumble that run fast.\" <\/em><\/p>\n<p>This note of caution comes from<\/p>","options":["Benvolio to Mercutio","Capulet to Paris","Friar to Romeo","Nurse to Juliet"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based in William Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>In the play, the dramatic significance of Mereutio's character is to&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["serve as a contrast to Romeo's","aid and abet Romeo's passion","annoy Tybalt","persuade Romeo to forget Rosaline"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Elliots's <em>Journey of the Magi<\/em>, the magi are aided on their journey by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["donkeys","horses","camels","chariots"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Keats' <em>On the Grasshopper and Cricket,<\/em> the frost of winter evenings is said to cause<\/strong><\/p>","options":["violence","luxury","silence","loneliness"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The subject matter of Wangusa's <em>A Taxi Driver on His Death<\/em> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the road","death","the vehicle","the driver"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Milton's On His Blindness teaches human beings to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["discountenance physical disabilities","regard disabilities as enduring","keep on struggling endlessly","use their talents sparingly"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Which of the following was not written by Chinua Achebe?<\/p>","options":["Girls at war","Anthills of the Salvador","No longer at Ease","Arrow of God"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>\"Even now that the typhoon of your tongue is blowing away the roof of my refuge, leaving me with showers of your kindness\"<\/p>\n<p>The most prominent figure of speech in the above is<\/p>","options":["hyperbole","contrast","metonymy","metaphor"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><em>\"I have been here for two weeks now and I've made friends As many as stars by the seashore\"<\/em><\/p>","options":["exaggeration","irony","simile","pathos"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Rhyme and rhythm are elements of<\/p>","options":["cultural poetry","musical poetry","colonial poetry","pastoral"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A mental picture created with words is referred to as&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["illusion","image","symbol","fiction"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a reason why the bats in <em>D.H Lawrence's \"Bat\"<\/em> are disgusting:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["they grin in their sleep","they hang upside down","they are like old rags","they are symbolic in China"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Gbemisola's&nbsp; <em>\"Naked Soles\"<\/em>, dancing is associated with&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["happiness","acropolis","suffering","thrones of thorns"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>According to Launko's poem&nbsp; <em>\"End of the war\"<\/em>, one of the following is not a result of the war<\/strong><\/p>","options":["silence of the battlefield","deserted houses","slums in the city","fallen rafters"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The atmosphere created in Elliot's <em>\"The Journey of the Magi\"<\/em> is that of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a birthday","an adventure","summer palaces","a pilgrimage"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Marvell's \"To His Coy Mistress\", the expression \"Time's winged chariot\" is both a<\/strong><\/p>","options":["synecdoche and metonymy","metaphor and personification","metaphor and hyperbole","personification and apostrophe"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The representation of a thing with something closely associated with it is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["epigram","metonymy","synecdoche","symbolism"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Parallelism involves similarity in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["structure","syntax","sound","lines"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>An iambic pentameter poem without a rhyme scheme is a&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["free verse","blind verse","blank verse","iambus"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a kind of imagery?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["offertory imagery","tactile imagery","visual imagery","kinesthetic imagery"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Gbemisola Adeoti's <em>\"Naked Soles\"<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>According to the poem, one of these does not pierce the soles.<\/p>","options":["Spikes","Glass chips","Pricks","Thrones of thorns"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Gbemisola Adeoti's <em>\"Naked Soles\"<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The atmosphere created in the poem is that of&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["disappointment","pain","rebellion","anger"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on T.S. Eliot's poem, \"The Journey of the Magi\".<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>What is not a reason the magi had a hard time in their journey?<\/p>","options":["The journey was becoming expensive","The camel men were abandoning the trip","There were no accommodation","They were no longer at ease"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on T.S. Eliot's poem, \"The Journey of the Magi\".<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The expression, <em>\"an old horse galloped in the meadow\"<\/em> is <\/p>","options":["a metaphor","an allusion","a synecdoche","a metonymy"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Strugnell's Sonnet (VI), the expression <em>\"I have no spare; henceforth I will hear the scar\",&nbsp;<\/em>refers to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["true swine","a big car","a heart","the poet's wings"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the causes of the tragedy in <em>Shakespeare's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">Romeo and Juliet<\/span><\/em> is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["quack doctor","the banishment","misinformation","too much love"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a figurative expression in <em><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">An African Thunderstorm<\/span><\/em> by Rubadirt?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["pregnant clouds","plaque of locusts","tattered flags","dangling breasts"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The line <em>\"Your mouth, O katty is a museum with many monuments\"<\/em> is both<\/p>","options":["metaphor and hyperbolic","a synecdoche and a metonymy","metaphoric and epigrammatic","a metaphor and an allusion"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A premiere is&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["a soap opera","the first play by a playwright","a play with social criticism in it","the first performance of a play"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A long narrative in which the fate of a community is dependent on the life and activities of the hero is<\/p>","options":["A tragedy","A legend","An epic","A historical narrative"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>Let my love like incense from Abel's palm rise to the golden temple of your face<\/em><\/p>\n<p>The above contains both<\/p>","options":["A simile and a paradox","A simile and a litotes","A simile and a metaphor","A simile and a personification"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Point of view in Literature is related to<\/p>","options":["the narrator","the author","the setting","the hero"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>Setting refers to both<\/p>","options":["time and place","place and space","place and mood","place and culture"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Buchi Emecheta's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">The joy of Motherhood<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>Nnu Ego, the daughter of Agbadi, don't be greedy, manage with Nnaife's income and look after your child, that is your duty. Be satisfied with his earnings, Let him do his duty.<\/em><\/p>\n<p>Who said the above?<\/p>","options":["Nwakusor","Nnu Ego","Adaku","Dilibe"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Buchi Emecheta's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">The joy of Motherhood<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>If you were not the mother of my sons, I would have taught you a lesson this evening, But don't push me too far; or I may still do it... Who brought me here? You think you can be defiant...<\/p>\n<p>The bone of contention above is&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["rent","sacrifice","feeding money","baby napkins"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Ahmed Yerima's \"Attahira\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Luggard wants to capture the Caliphate so that it will not fall into the hands or authority of<\/p>","options":["Americans","Frenchmen","German","Italians"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Ahmed Yerima's \"Attahira\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The land dispute in the play is inserted to demostrate<\/p>","options":["The authority of the Caliph over all land matters","the unreasonableness of Sarkin Zango and Sark in Fatake","the judicial wisdom of the Caliph","the importance of arable land in the Caliphate"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on William Shakespeare's \"Hamlet\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>Ber: sit down awhile and let us once again absail your ears, that are so fortified against our story, What we have two nights seen.<\/em><\/p>\n<p>The speaker and His friends have seen:<\/p>","options":["a soothsayer foretelling the death of Polonius","a ghost","a heavy mist surrounding the castle","a witch flying in the dark"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on William Shakespeare's \"Hamlet\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>... O most wicked speed, to post with such dexterity to incentuous sheets! It is not nor it cannot come to good...<\/em><\/p>\n<p>In the above lines, Hamlet is alluding to<\/p>","options":["the quick succession to the throne by Claudius","the marriage of his mother to his uncle","the failure to deliver a letter to Norway","the use of unclean sheets to bury his dead father"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Femi Ademuluyi's \"The New Man\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The eventual conflict between Ayo Badejo and the people of Ipaja was most pointedly foretold by<\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Prophet Elijah","Hon. Bulawayo","Chief Layeni","the school Headmaster"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Femi Ademuluyi's \"The New Man\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A strong or prominent feature of <em>\"The New Man\"<\/em> is&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["sermons","political rallies","festivals","violence"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Femi Ademuluyi's \"The New Man\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The author's use of his name as a character in the novel is intended to&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["display his mastery of fiction","give the story an impression of truth","displace the prominence of the hero","convert the story into a historical document"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Femi Ademuluyi's \"The New Man\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The religious life of the people of Ipaja could be described as&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["pure and devout","exclusively heathenish","contentious and rowdy","a mixture of superstitions and Christian beliefs"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Thomas Hardy's \"Tess of the D'Urbervilles\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The society decribed in the novel could be descrbed as<\/p>","options":["class-conscious","highly religious","egalitarian","highly prosperous"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Thomas Hardy's \"Tess of the D'Urbervilles\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>John Durbeyfield's behaviour after hearing of his noble ancestry shows him up<\/p>","options":["unbothered by past events","constant in character","foolishly excitable","an ancestor worshipper"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Thomas Hardy's \"Tess of the D'Urbervilles\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>\"Tess of the D'Urbervilles\"<\/em> is mainly set in&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["an industrialized city","a mining community","an agrarian community","a fishing village"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Thomas Hardy's \"Tess of the D'Urbervilles\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The three brothers who saw Tess and her friends when they were dancing are named&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Angel, Frederick and Cuthbert","William, Alex and Felix","John, Filbert and Bobby","Felix, Angel and Cuthbert"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Thomas Hardy's \"Tess of the D'Urbervilles\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Angel Clare's choice of Tess as his wife is received by his parents with<\/p>","options":["warmth and excitement","anger and rejection","doubt and reservation","cold and indifference"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Brutu's poem \"A troubadour I Traverse\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>In this poem, the poet's image of the land is that of<\/p>","options":["a beloved woman that is also dangerous","a harsh, unfeeling desert","an unfaithful treacherous male friend","a war-devastated terrain"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Brutu's poem \"A troubadour I Traverse\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The poet's feelings are inspired&nbsp; by his struggle against<\/p>","options":["religious fanatics","colonialism","injustice","communism"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Shakespeare's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">Romeo and Juliet<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Romeo's melancholic mood at the play's beginning is because<\/p>","options":["he is unhappy with the quarrel between the Capulets and the Montagues","he find the morning air disagreeable to his health","he cannot convince Benrolio to follow him to the party","he is suffering from the pangs of unrequited love"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Shakespeare's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">Romeo and Juliet<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Which of the following phrases represents most accurately Old Capulet's reaction to Juliet's refusal to marry Paris?<\/p>","options":["gentle and tolerant","indifferent and rough","impatient and tyrannical","boastful and unctuous"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on George Orwell's 1984<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>In this novel, the term \"proles\" is&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["a term for underground moles","a reference to subversive elements","a term of contempt for the common people","gangsters who oppose big brother"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on George Orwell's 1984<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>In this novel, Orwell creates the picture of&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["a welfare state","a brutal totalitarian state","a community of strong worshippers","a nation of vibrant and loving citizens"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Ferdinand Oyono's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">The Old Man and the Medal<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Meka's initial reaction to the commandment's invitation is one of<\/p>","options":["joy","excitement","anger","apprehension"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Ferdinand Oyono's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">The Old Man and the Medal<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The author's description of Meka's neighbourhood and their way of life in the village shows <\/p>","options":["his love and admiration for them","his contempt for and disgust with them","his familiarity with African traditions","that Africans do not have a stable family life"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Buchi Emecheta's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">The Joys of Motherhood<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Nuego's First reaction to Nname betrays<\/p>","options":["elation","disgust","contentment","familiarlty"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on Buchi Emecheta's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">The Joys of Motherhood<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Nnuego's character could be summarized as<\/p>","options":["extremely and unreasonably self-sacrificing","deliberately and negatively scheming","extremely selfish","irresponsible and care free"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The main purpose of a satire is to<\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["heighten the personality of the main character in a story","attack the government","incite the reader to rebellion","ridicule or treat a subject or idea with contempt"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A prologue usually occurs at the&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["middle of a poem","end of a novel","beginning of a play","none of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>In a literary work, the character whom the hero struggles against is called his<\/p>","options":["alter ego","opposite","mentor","antagonist"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Literary Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>My love is like a red rose<\/em><\/p>\n<p><em>O&nbsp; my love is like the melody<\/em><\/p>\n<p><em>That's sweetly played in tune<\/em><\/p>\n<p>The main literary device employed in the above lines is&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["antithesis","simile","metaphor","abstraction"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Out, Out, thou strumpet fortune! All ye gods,&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>In general synod, take away her power,<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Break all the spokes and fellies from her wheel<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>And bowl the round knave down the hill of heaven<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>As low as to the friends<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p>In the above lines, the persona is<\/p>","options":["enchanted with fortune","praying to the gods for good fortune","intensely angry with fortune","none of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Out, Out, thou strumpet fortune! All ye gods,&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>In general synod, take away her power,<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Break all the spokes and fellies from her wheel<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>And bowl the round knave down the hill of heaven<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>As low as to the friends<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em>The device adopted in talking of fortune is<\/em><\/p>","options":["pomposity","analogy","axiom","personification"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>The rivers and streams shrank; vaporized into a leaven that horded the precious drops; beast and man panted in the heat; the earth's surface wore wrinkles and deep cracks, parched and deviod of a blade of green nature.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The description above is concerned with<\/p>","options":["famine","drought","forest fires","ravages of war"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"}]